<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
	<properties>
		<title>Features</title>
		<author email="francois-xavier.bonnet@smile.fr">Francois-Xavier Bonnet</author>
	</properties>
	<body>
		<section name="Features">
			<subsection name="Blocks and templates">
				<p>
					Any web application can be used as a provider. The master
					application will be
					able to use blocks and templates delimited with special HTML comments.
				</p>
			</subsection>
			<subsection name="Cross technologies">
				<p>
					As we only use HTML comments inside provider applications, a
					provider application
					may have been developed with any technology,
					including Java, PHP on .NET.
	</p>
			</subsection>
			<subsection name="Reverse proxy">
				<p>
					The kit contains a reverse-proxy servlet that can be used to
					retrieve static contents
					from the provider applications (images, css,
					js...). For better performance, you may
					prefer to use Apache mod_proxy
					powerfull module but the reverse-proxy servlet may as
					well be used in a
					production environment with good performance.
	</p>
			</subsection>
			<subsection name="Aggregator">
				<p>
					The aggregator is a reverse-proxy servlet that can parse the pages
					on the fly and process
					inclusion instructions inserted in the pages by
					the applications as tags.
	</p>
			</subsection>
			<subsection name="ESI 1.0 specification support">
				<p>
					In addition to its native syntax using HTML comments, the Website Assembling
					Toolkit partially supports ESI specification (for now, only esi:include and
					esi comments are supported).
	</p>
			</subsection>
			<subsection name="Xpath expressions and XSLT">
				<p>
					One of the latest features is the possibility to retrieve elements using xpath
					expressions and to apply on-the-fly XSLT transformations to retrieved elements.
	</p>
			</subsection>
			<subsection name="Cache">
				<p>
					In order to improve performance, the tool can be configured to use a
					cache (the underlying cache
					implementation is the open source library OsCache). Cached entries may be
					long-lived
					or short-lived
					depending on your needs and depending on the provider
					application.
	</p>
			</subsection>
			<subsection name="User context">
				<p>
					While calling the provider application, you may want to send
					informations about
					the currently connected user for personalization.
					The tool lets you transfer the
					user id, user locale and any key/value
					list. These informations will be automatically
					appended as request
					parameters to the http request.
	</p>
			</subsection>
			<subsection name="Single Sign On with CAS">
				<p>
					The kit supports CAS protocol using the
					<a
						href="http://www.ja-sig.org/products/cas/overview/proxy_auth/index.html">proxy authentication mode</a>
					and the JA-SIG CAS client.
				</p>
			</subsection>
		</section>
	</body>
</document>