<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "-//APACHE//DTD Documentation V1.1//EN" "document-v11.dtd"
[
  <!ENTITY % xmlsec_entities SYSTEM "../xmlsec_entities.ent"> 
  %xmlsec_entities; 
]>
<!--
Copyright 2003-2004 The Apache Software Foundation

Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
You may obtain a copy of the License at

    http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
limitations under the License.
-->

<document> 
  <header> 
    <title>The Java section</title> 
  </header> 
  <body> 
    <section>
    <title>Version 1.4.1 Released</title> 
        <p>
		  Version 1.4.1 of the Java library has been released. This a bugfix release that 
          contains a major bugfix to the canonicalization engine introduced in the 1.4 release. 
          It is recommended that 1.4 users upgrade to the new version as signatures containing 
          non ascii characters created by this library are not according to the standard, and will be only validated by 1.4 library. 
        </p>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Version 1.4 Released</title>
		<p>
		  Version 1.4 of the Java library has been released. 
		  The main changes for this version are:
		</p>
		<ul>
          <li>Implementation of the standard API JSR105</li>
          <li>Rewritten c14n that increases performance for signature 
          with node-set transformations.</li>
          <li>Memory footprint reduction and several bugfixes</li>
         </ul> 
         <p> Refer to the 
		  <link href="site:changes">changelog</link> for more information.
		</p>      
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Overview of the Java Library</title>
      <p>
	The &packagenamelong; &packageversion; supports
	<jump href="ext:w3c/xmldsig_java_supported">&supp_java_dsig;
	</jump> and 
	<jump href="ext:w3c/xmlenc_java_supported">&supp_java_enc;
	</jump>
      </p>
      <p>
	As of version 1.4, the Java library supports the standard Java API
	<jump href="http://jcp.org/jsr/detail/105.jsp">
	  JSR-105: XML Digital Signature APIs
	</jump> for creating and validating XML Signatures. A standard Java
	API for XML Encryption 
	<jump href="http://jcp.org/jsr/detail/106.jsp">
	  JSR-106: XML Digital Encryption APIs
	</jump> is in progress and is not final, so this
	API is not yet supported. You can continue to use the existing
	non-standard APIs in the Java Library (there are no plans
	to discontinue or deprecate them), but you should consider moving
	to the standard APIs.
      </p>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Old News</title>
      <p>
        Version 1.3 released on 28 October 2005. Improves performance and 
	memory usage over 1.2, and includes several bugfixes.
      </p>
      <p>
        Version 1.2.1 released on 28 February 2005. It is a bugfix version 
	over 1.2 and it is recomended to upgrade to this version. 
      </p>
      <p>
        Version 1.2 released on 11 December 2004. Improves the performance and 
	memory usage over 1.1 release together with an easier integration of 
	JCE providers.
      </p>
      <p>
	Version 1.1 released on 7 April 2004. Includes a beta implementation
	of XML Encryption together with minor bug fixes for the XML Signature
	code.
      </p>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>JDK 1.4 issues</title>
      <p>
	If you use JDK 1.4 and want to use this software, be sure that Xalan is
	properly installed. Check the <jump
	  href="site:java/installation">installation guide</jump>!!!
      </p>
      <p>
	I have so many complaints from people who argue that the software
	throws exceptions during running the examples or during unit
	testing. This package NEEDS a Xalan version after 2.2D13 (and SUN
	shipped his JDK 1.4.0 final with a Xalan beta!). I started integrating
	the installation guide into the exception messages cause it seems that
	people don't have a look at the installation guide. 
      </p>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
