<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "-//APACHE//DTD Documentation V1.1//EN" "document-v11.dtd">
<!--
Copyright 2003-2004 The Apache Software Foundation

Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
You may obtain a copy of the License at

    http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
limitations under the License.
-->
<document>
  <header>
    <title>C++ Library Documentation</title>
  </header>
  
  <body>
    <section>
      <title>Version 1.2 Released</title>
      <p>
        The Apache XML Security team are proud to announce the release
        of version 1.2 of the xml-security-c library.  This is the first
        version of the library to provide processing and handling of 
        <link href="http://www.w3.org/2001/XKMS/">XML Key Management
          Specification (XKMS)</link> (currently XML Key Information Service
        Specification - XKISS - only) messages together with a command
        line client for performing XKMS requests and reading/dumping
        XKMS messages.
      </p>
      <p>
        The team were involved in <link href="http://www.w3c.org">World Wide
          Web Consortium (w3c)</link> interoperability testing with
        a reference XKMS server built using the xml-security-c library.
      </p>
      <p>
        This version also includes a number of other changes and bugfixes,
        including updates to support Xerces 2.6 with Xalan 1.9.
        See <link href="../changes.html">changes.html</link> for more
        information.
      </p>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Overview of the C++ Library</title>
      <p>
        The C++ library is an implementation of the XML Digital Signature
        specification.  It is designed to be easily ported to new platforms,
        and has been tested on Solaris, Linux, FreeBSD, NetBSD and Windows.
      </p>
      <p>
        The library makes use of the Apache XML project's Xerces-C XML Parser
        and Xalan-C XSLT processor.  The latter is used for processing XPath
        and XSLT transforms.  The use of Xalan-C is optional, but without it,
        XPath and XSLT transformations cannot be performed.
      </p>
      <p>
        In addition, the library currently uses OpenSSL to provide 
        cryptographic functionality.  The cryptographic interface is
        implemented via a thin wrapper layer, and a development version of
		an implementation for the Windows Cryptographic API has also been
		implemented.
      </p>
    </section>
	<section>
	  <title>Old News</title>
      <section>
        <title>News - March 2004</title>
        <p>
          Version 1.1 of the C++ library has been released.  Supporting
          Xerces 2.5, 2.4 and 2.3 together with Xalan 1.6 and 1.7, this
          version provides :
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>Beta implementation of XML Encryption</li>
          <li>Improved support for Windows Crypto API</li>
          <li>Bug fixes to Signature implementation</li>
        </ul>
      </section>
	  <section>
		<title>May 2003</title>
		<p>
		  Beta 0.2 has been released.  It covers :
		</p>
		<ul>
		  <li>some minor bug-fixes in the	code and the UNIX build system</li>
		  <li>a first cut at a Windows Crypto API provider interface</li>
		  <li>methods to extract information from signature objects; and</li>
		  <li>updates to tools to allow (and demonstrate) use of Windows CAPI
			and new extraction methods</li>
		</ul>
		<p>
		  Beta 0.2 is has been tested with Xerces-C v2.2 and the newly 
		  released Xalan-C v1.5.
		</p>
	  </section>
	  <section>
		<title>February 2003</title>
		<p>
		  The C++ library has now been fully transferred into the Apache XML
		  project.  It was previously hosted on SourceForge.
		</p>
		<p>
		  The first release under Apache is 0.10.  This is a Beta release,
		  with fairly complete documentation, and a stable code base.  It
		  fully validates the various interop documents held in the xml-security
		  CVS, with the exception of those related to :
		</p>
		<ul>
		  <li>MD5 Digests (to be added in next point release)</li>
		  <li>XPath Filter (to be added in next point release)</li>
		  <li>XML Encryption (to be added post 1.00 release)</li>
		</ul>
	  </section>
	  <section>
		<title>News - August 2003</title>
		<p>
		  Version 1.00 of the library has now been released.  It features :
		</p>
		<ul>
		  <li>the first stable release</li>
		  <li>full implementation of all mandatory requirements of DSIG</li>
		  <li>implementation of canonicalised XML</li>
		  <li>implementation of exclusive-canonicalised XML</li>
		  <li>implementation of XPath-filter</li>
		  <li>FreeBSD, NetBSD and Cygwin builds</li>
		</ul>
		<p>
		  Version 1.00 is has been tested with Xerces-C v2.2 and the newly 
		  released Xalan-C v1.6.  Xerces-C v2.3 is also supported.  Note that
		  versions of Xalan prior to v1.6 are not supported (due to the new
		  changed location of include files).
		</p>
	  </section>
	</section>
  </body>
</document>

<!-- Keep this comment at the end of the file
Local variables:
mode: xml
sgml-omittag:nil
sgml-shorttag:nil
sgml-namecase-general:nil
sgml-general-insert-case:lower
sgml-minimize-attributes:nil
sgml-always-quote-attributes:t
sgml-indent-step:2
sgml-indent-data:t
sgml-parent-document:nil
sgml-exposed-tags:nil
sgml-local-catalogs:nil
sgml-local-ecat-files:nil
End:
-->
