<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "-//APACHE//DTD Documentation V1.1//EN" "document-v11.dtd">
<!--
Copyright 2003-2004 The Apache Software Foundation

Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
You may obtain a copy of the License at

    http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
limitations under the License.
-->

<document>
  <header>
    <title>Tools</title>
  </header>
  <body>
	<section>
	  <title>Provided Tools</title>
	  <p>
		A number of very simple "tools" (really examples) are provided with
		the XML Security library.  These can be used either to provide examples
		of how to use the library or as simple utilities in their own right for
		performing canonicalisation and signature functions.
	  </p>
	  <p>
		The tools are :
	  </p>
	  <ul>
		<li><em>c14n</em> - A tool to output a Canonicalised version of an 
		  input document.</li>
		<li><em>checksig</em> - A tool to validate a signature in an XML
		  input document</li>
		<li><em>templatesign</em> - A tool to sign an XML document that already
		  has the &lt;Signature&gt; structure installed, but needs the references
		  hashed and the SignatureValue set.</li>
		<li><em>txfmout</em> - A tool to take an XML Signature and output
		  the fully transformed references to stdout or a nominated file</li>
		<li><em>threadTest</em> - A Windows only program that runs up a number
		  of threads which simultaneously sign and validate documents.  A
		  number of documents are modified in between (to cause the signature
		  validation to fail).</li>
		<li><em>siginf</em> - A tool to read in an XML Signature and dump
		  various details about the signature and references to the terminal
		</li>
		<li><em>cipher</em> - A tool to encrypt and decrypt XML documents.
		</li>
		<li><em>xklient</em> - A tool to generate and process XKMS messages.
          Can be used to send XKMS requests to XKMS servers over SOAP 1.1/1.2
          and HTML and to dump the results to screen.
		</li>
	  </ul>
	  <p>
		The tools can all be run with no command line arguments to see their
		parameters.
	  </p>
	  <p>
		One extra "tool" is provided - <em>xtest</em>.  This is really a testing
		program that exercises various capabilities of the library and compares
		the results with known good results.
	  </p>
	</section>
  </body>
</document>
<!-- Keep this comment at the end of the file
Local variables:
mode: xml
sgml-omittag:nil
sgml-shorttag:nil
sgml-namecase-general:nil
sgml-general-insert-case:lower
sgml-minimize-attributes:nil
sgml-always-quote-attributes:t
sgml-indent-step:2
sgml-indent-data:t
sgml-parent-document:nil
sgml-exposed-tags:nil
sgml-local-catalogs:nil
sgml-local-ecat-files:nil
End:
-->
