<?xml version="1.0" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE s1 SYSTEM "sbk:/style/dtd/document.dtd">

<s1 title="Readme">
	<s2 title="News">
		<p>Version 1.0.4 released on 15. July 2002; minor improvements. The most significant is that people who did not install Xalan properly under JDK 1.4.0 get a more specific error message. It uses the most recent version of the BouncyCastle JCE now. </p>
		<p>Version 1.0.3 now supports new W3C specs:</p>
		<ul>
		<li><jump href="http://www.w3.org/TR/2002/REC-xml-exc-c14n-20020718/">Exclusive XML Canonicalization Version 1.0, W3C Recommendation 18 July 2002</jump>. (There is no interop to test vector <jump href="http://www.w3.org/Signature/2002/02/01-exc-c14n-interop.html">Y4</jump> because of a problem in Xalan)</li>
		<li><jump href="http://www.w3.org/TR/2002/CR-xmldsig-filter2-20020718/">XML-Signature XPath Filter 2.0, W3C Candidate Recommendation 18 July 2002 </jump></li>
		</ul>
		<p>Canonicalization is written completely new: it's about 5-80 times faster than the implementation in version 1.0.2. It's highly recommended to upgrade to the new version. </p>
	</s2>
	<s2 title="JDK 1.4 issues">
		<p>If you use JDK 1.4 and want to use this software, be sure that Xalan is properly installed. Check the bottom of the <jump href="install.html">installation guide</jump>!!!</p>
		<p>I have so many complaints from people who argue that the software throws exceptions during running the examples or during unit testing. This package NEEDS a Xalan version after 2.2D13 (and SUN shipped his JDK 1.4.0 final with a Xalan beta!). I started integrating the installation guide into the exception messages cause it seems that people don't have a look at the installation guide. </p>
	</s2>
	<s2 title="XML Security Release">
		<p>The &packagenamelong; &packageversion; supports the <jump href="http://www.w3.org/TR/2002/REC-xmldsig-core-20020212/">XML-Signature Syntax and Processing</jump> recommendation.</p>
                <p>Note that there is no standard API avaliable at the moment. SUN is working on a JAVA Specification Request <jump href="http://jcp.org/jsr/detail/105.jsp">JSR-105: XML Digital Signature APIs</jump> on an API for XML Signature and <jump href="http://jcp.org/jsr/detail/106.jsp">JSR-106: XML Digital Encryption APIs</jump>, but until now, nothing has been published. So, this software does <em>not</em> conform to any of these specifications.</p>
	</s2>
	<s2 title="License Information">
		<p>The XML Security package is available in both source code and precompiled binary (JAR files) form. Both  packages are made available under the <jump href='LICENSE.txt'>Apache Software License</jump>.</p>
	</s2>
	<s2 title="Download">
		<p>You can download the source and binary packages in the <jump href='http://xml.apache.org/security/dist/'>dist</jump> directory.</p>
	</s2>
	<s2 title="Sample programs">
		<p>This software can be used to create and verify arbitrary forms of XML Signatures. The documentation available here is not very huge; my first approach is to supply usage examples which are available in the <code>src_samples/</code> directory to give interested users a first starting point to jump-start with XML Signature. NOTE: The samples divide into two groups: Samples that <em>create</em> and samples that <em>verify</em> Signatures. Eventually, you should adjust the verifying program to another filename if you get <code>FileNotFoundException</code>s.</p>
	</s2>
	<s2 title="Mailing lists">
		<p>There exists a mailing list which you can subscribe to ask questions:</p>
                <p>The <jump href="http://xml.apache.org/mail.html">ezmlm mailing list controller</jump> accepts commands by sending emails to it, generally like the following:</p>
                <ul>
                <li><jump href="mailto:security-dev-subscribe@xml.apache.org">security-dev-subscribe</jump> to subscribe your current email address to the list</li>
                <li><jump href="mailto:security-dev-unsubscribe@xml.apache.org">security-dev-unsubscribe</jump> to <em>un</em>subscribe your *current* email address from the list</li>
                <li><jump href="mailto:security-dev-help@xml.apache.org">security-dev-help</jump> to get Help on mailing list commands</li>
                </ul>
                <p>An archive of this list is kept under <jump href="http://news.gmane.org/thread.php?group=gmane.text.xml.security.devel">http://news.gmane.org/thread.php?group=gmane.text.xml.security.devel</jump></p>
	</s2>
	<s2 title="Contact information">
		<p>For comments about the software please send them to the author <code><jump href="mailto:geuer-pollmann@nue.et-inf.uni-siegen.de">geuer-pollmann@nue.et-inf.uni-siegen.de</jump></code></p>
	</s2>
</s1>
